Finding Aid for the Leo Smit Score Collection, circa 1940-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Compositions by Leo Smit, 1943-1998, I; Item 1-104
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Celestial thrush The celestial thrush :twelve songs about birds and music: for mezzo-soprano (or soprano) and piano 1996, 1 score (43 leaves); 28 cm (Box 5, Item 042)
    Contents: I was a phoebe--nothing more (9/13/88) -- The bird her punctual music brings (10/7/88) -- The earth has many keys (10/6/88) -- The bobolink is gone (9/22/88) -- A train went through a burial gate (10/5/88) -- I cannot dance upon my toes (10/4/88) -- Upon his saddle sprung a bird (10/2/88) -- Better--than music!--For I--who heard it (10/2/88) -- Bind me--I still can sing (9/28/88) -- Within my garden rides a bird (9/28/88) -- Heart, not so heavy as mine (9/25/88) -- I shall keep singing! (9/28/88).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Childe Emilie Childe Emilie :fourteen songs about memories and fantasies of childhood: for mezzo-soprano (or soprano) and piano 1996, 1 score (41 pages); 28 cm (Box 5, Item 043)
    Cycle 1 from the Ecstatic Pilgrimage.
    "For Rosalind Rees."
    Contents: I was the slightest in the house (3/8/89) -- Through lane it lay--through bramble (4/1/89) -- It troubled me as once I was (4/2?/89) -- The child's faith is new (3/17/89) -- Softened by time's consummate plush (4/17/89) -- Papa above! (4/14/89) -- We talked as girls do (4/4/89) -- They shut me up in prose (3/19/89) -- I cried at pity--not at pain (3/12/89) -- Let us play yesterday (4/10/89) -- A loss of something ever felt I (3/31/89) -- Good morning--midnight (4/8/89) -- Up life's hill with my little bundle (5/11?/89) -- I'm ceded--I've stopped being theirs (7/15/89).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. White diadem Cycle V :the purple diadem (the poet speaks) 1989, 1 score (26 leaves); 28 cm; Alternate title: Purple diadem Alternate title: Poet speaks (Box 5, Item 044)
    Title from preliminary list of contents.
    For high voice and piano.
    Title later changed to the White diadem, which became Cycle 6 of the Ecstatic pilgrimage.
    Contents: I reckon--when I count at all (7/5/89) -- I dwell in possibility (10/2/89) -- This was a poet (7/7/89) -- The poets light but lamps (7/9/89) -- I would not paint a picture (7/11/89) -- The martyr poets--did not tell (7/10/89) -- Shall I take thee--the poet said (7/12/89) -- To pile like thunder to its close (6/30/89) -- Me--come! My dazzled face (4/20/89).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. White diadem. I dwell in possibility; arranged I dwell in possibility :for baritone and guitar 1994, 2 leaves of manuscript music; 28 cm (Box 5, Item 045)
    Originally for mezzo-soprano (or soprano) and piano as part of Cycle 6 (White diadem) of Ecstatic pilgrimage.
    "1989/94."
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. White diadem. I reckon, when I count at all; arranged I reckon--when I count at all :for baritone + guitar 1994, 3 leaves of manuscript music; 28 cm (Box 5, Item 046)
    Originally for mezzo-soprano (or soprano) and piano, as part of Cycle 6 (White diadem) of Ecstatic pilgrimage.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Exequy :for string trio 1985, 1 score (18 pages); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 047)
    Holograph (Ink).
    Originally issued as Scena cambiata, for trombone, viola and violoncello, 1980.
    "In memory of Igor Stravinsky."
    "July 13, 1985"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Exequy :for string trio 1985, 1 score (21 pages); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 048)
    Originally issued as Scena Cambiata for trombone, viola, and violoncello, 1980.
    Contents: Recitativo -- Cavata -- Rice[r]car -- Corale -- Cadenza finale.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Exequy :for string trio 1985, 3 manuscript parts; 35-38 cm (Box 5, Item 049)
    Title supplied by cataloger.
    Parts incomplete; portions of score meant to be read by players from full score.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Exequy :for string trio 1985, 3 manuscript parts; 36 cm (Box 5, Item 050)
    Originally issued as Scena cambiata for trombone, viola, and violoncello, 1980.
    Contents: Recitativo -- Cavata -- Ricercar -- Corale -- Cadenza finale.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Pushkin romances. I loved you once I loved you once 1952, 1 manuscript score (2 leaves); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 051)
    Words by Alexander Pushkin.
    For medium voice and piano.
    The first of the composer's Three Pushkin romances.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Pushkin romances Three Pushkin romances: voice + piano 1952, 1 manuscript score ([11] pages); 25 cm; Alternate title: Pushkin romances (Box 5, Item 051a)
    Contents: I loved you once (July 27, 1952) -- Casual gift (August 18, 1952) -- I've lived to bury my desires (August 19, 1952).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Pushkin romances. I loved you once I loved you once 1952, 1 ms. score (2 leaves); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 051b)
    The first of the composer’s Three Pushkin romances.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Immortality songs Three immortality songs (1996) :for baritone and guitar 1996, 1 manuscript score ([6] pages in various pagings); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 052)
    "In memory of Jan DeGaetani"--Caption.
    "Leucadia, CA, 1996"--Colophon.
    Contents: That such have died enable us -- Extol thee--could I? -- I went to heaven.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Immortality songs. Extol thee Extol thee--could I? Then I will 1989, 1 manuscript score (2 leaves); 28 cm (Box 5, Item 053)
    No. 2 of Three immortality songs.
    "7.21.89"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 I went to heaven 1989, 1 manuscript score (2 pages); 28 cm (Box 5, Item 054)
    Words by Emily Dickinson.
    "3.13.89"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 In woods :1978: for oboe, harp and percussion (one player) 1978, 1 manuscript score (51 pages); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 055)
    Photocopy of instrumentation page, with annotations by Jan Williams inserted.
    "Composed for Nora Post, Mario Falco and Jan Williams and dedicated to Nils Vigeland"--Insert.
    "January 3, 1978 - Pacific Palisades, California"--Colophon.
    "Rental Library, Carl Fischer"--Sticker on cover.
    Publisher no. 1713 from label on cover.
    Contents: Murmurations -- Bird-clocks/Nightsinger -- Oracular -- (Branch) -- Crow omen -- In deep woods.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 In woods Trio (1977-78): oboe, harp, percussion 1978, 1 manuscript score (29 leaves); 37 cm (Box 5, Item 055b)
    Contents: Murmurations -- Bird-clocks/Nightsinger -- Oracular -- Branch -- Crow omen.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 In woods :1978: for oboe, harp and percussion (one player) 1978, 1 manuscript score (50 pages); 28-36 cm (Box 5, Item 056)
    "Composed for Nora Post, Mario Falcao and Jan Williams and dedicated to Nils Vigeland"--Title page verso.
    "January 3, 1978 - Pacific Palisades, CA"--Colophon.
    "Rental Library, Carl Fischer, Inc ..."
    Includes diagram of stage setup.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 The last hour :settings of five Emily Dickinson poems for mixed chorus a cappella 1988, 1 score (17 pages); 28 cm (Box 5, Item 057)
    "In memory of Harriet Greif."
    Duration: circa 9:00.
    Contents: Tie the strings to my life, my lord (10.12.88) -- Dying in the night (10.14.88) -- If I can stop one heart from breaking (10.16.88) -- If I shouldn't be alive (10.17.88) -- This is my letter to the world (10.17.88).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 A light piece =Un pezzo leggiero: for violin and piano 1948, 1 manuscript score (14 pages); 35 cm; Alternate title: Pezzo leggiero (Box 5, Item 058)
    "To L.L.G."
    "Composed May 3, 1945, revised June 13, 1948, New York City."
    "May 3, 1945, June 13, 1948, New York"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Lizzie in wonderland :four characteristic pieces for harp solo 1974, 1 manuscript score (7 pages); 36 cm (Box 5, Item 059)
    "Edited, fingered [by] Lucile Laurence"--Caption.
    Includes performance markings.
    "For Elizabeth Rosenthal."
    "Gran Quivira, New Mexico, 3/15/74"--Colophon.
    Contents: Prelude: "Who in the world am I?" -- Air: "Good-bye, poor little feet" -- March (Boots for Christmas): Lizzie's right foot, Esq., Hearthrug, Near the fender (with Lizzie's love) -- Jig: "But I can kick a little."
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Madrigals for a Roman lady Four madrigals for a Roman lady :for mixed chorus a cappella 1965, 1 score (22 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 060)
    "1955/65."
    "Carl Fischer Rental Library"--Sticker on title page.
    Contents: Kisses -- Elegy on her sparrow -- On her inconstancy -- Love's return.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Magic water: a chamber opera in one act, six scenes 1978, 1 score (b, 99 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 061)
    "Magic Water is based on N. Hawthorne's short story, Dr. Heidegger's Experiment"--Page b.
    Duration: circa 14-15:00.
    "June 15, 1978 Solana Beach, California"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Magic water. Vocal score Magic water: a chamber opera in one act and six scenes 1978, 1 manuscript vocal score (43 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 062)
    Synopsis ([4] leaves) inserted.
    "Based on Hawthorne's short story, Dr. Heidegger's Experiment"--Insert.
    Includes markings: marked for performance, changes and additions to music and text.
    "May 21, 1978 Del Mar, California"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Martha through the looking-glass :three pieces for piano solo 1974, 1 score (3 pages); 28 cm (Box 6, Item 063)
    "Words in confidence from the composer to the performer"--Typescript leaf attached.
    Duration: circa 5:00.
    "Feb., 1974 Los Angeles, California."
    Contents: The white knight -- "It's my own invention" -- The upside-down deal box.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Martha through the looking-glass :three pieces for piano solo 1982, 1 score (3 pages); 28 cm (Box 6, Item 064)
    "1175."
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Memento '51 :for vibraphone + bass 1995, 1 score (9 pages); 36 cm; Alternate title: Memento 1951 (Box 6, Item 065)
    "Commissioned by Naomi and Paul Pascal for their son David and their daughter-in-law Susan and dedicated to all four friends."--Prefatory page.
    "6 Jan. 95 Leucadia, circa"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 A mountain eulogy :from Peer Gynt: for speaker and chamber orchestra 1979, 1 score (38 pages); 40 cm (Box 6, Item 066)
    "A Mountain Eulogy was commissioned by the State Arena Theatre for Paul Schmidt and Yvar Mikhashoff in memory of Vera Brynner"--Page preceding score.
    Publisher no. from label on cover: 1539.
    Duration: circa 16:00.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Petals of Amaranth (1995) :ten pieces for viola and piano 1995, 1 score (24 pages); 28 cm (Box 6, Item 067)
    "These pieces are free transcriptions of ten of my Emily Dickinson songs, originally for mezzo-soprano and piano"--Prefatory page.
    "March 28, 1995 Leucadia, CA"--Colophon.
    Duration: circa 20:00.
    Contents: That first day -- Too late, dear? -- Conversation in the grave -- The road of pain -- Ruby-lit heaven -- The death-fly -- Suicide! -- Madness? -- Ascension to the clouds -- The realm of you.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Poems of M. Willieme Three poems of M. Willieme :soprano + piano 1994, 1 score (17 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 068)
    Title from manilla folder.
    "Feb. 27, 1994 Leucadia, CA"--Colophon.
    Contents: And all the air is still -- Bus tour: Boston in the rain -- In the celestial computer.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Quartet, strings String quartet 1983, 4 parts; 43 cm (Box 6, Item 069)
    Manuscript (Vellum).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Quartet, strings String quartet 1983, 4 parts; 43 cm (Box 6, Item 069a)
    Manuscript (Ozalid reproductions).
    Parts extensively marked for performance.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Quartet, strings Quartet (1938-1983) 1983, 1 score (54 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 069b)
    Changes to score marked in pencil and black ink.
    End of Mvt. II: "11/25/82"; end of Mvt. III: "12.10.83."
    Mvt. II (pages 43-54) copied as leaves on narrower paper.
    Movements as marked on enclosing folder: 1. Fantasy, 2. Chorale, 3. Retrospective.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Scena cambiata :for trombone, viola and violoncello 1980, 1 score (17 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 070)
    "Commissioned by Yvar Mikhashoff for Cambiata, Inc., and dedicated to Liisa Van Duyts."
    "Feb. 20, 1980/Buffalo, N.Y."--Colophon.
    Contents: Recitativo -- Cavata -- Fuga -- Corale -- Cadenza.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Scena cambiata (Sketches) Scena cambiata :for viola, cello and trombone: sketches 1980 1980, 1 score [22] pages; 36 cm (Box 6, Item 071)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 So well, that I can live without 198-?, 1 score (1 leaf); 28 cm (Box 6, Item 072)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Sonatas, piano Sonata in one movement for piano solo :1951-55 1966, 1 score (16 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 073)
    "To Francis Thorne."
    "To Mr. Leo Smit for corrections, 7/6/66."
    "Ok for engraving, 4/14/66."
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Sonatas, piano (4 hands) Piano sonata, four hands 1987, 1 score (41 leaves); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 074)
    Manuscript (partially ink, part photocopy).
    Contains corrections: score prepared by more than one person.
    "8-9-87"--Colophon.
    Contents: Pastoral -- Scherzo -- Romanza -- Intermezzo -- Fuga finale.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Sonatas, cello Sonata for solo cello 1982, 1 score (27 pages); 36 cm (Box 6, Item 075)
    "For Roger Lebow."
    "For Roger, with affection from Leo 1.8.83"--Crossed out on title page.
    "7.14.82 Del Mar, CA"--Colophon.
    Score contains markings, including changes, bowings, fingerings, and tempo indications.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Sonatas, cello Sonata for solo cello 1982, 1 score (18 pages); 28 cm (Box 6, Item 076)
    Computer-notated music.
    "For Roger Lebow"--Caption.
    "7/14/82 Del Mar, CA"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Songs and refrains. Selections Songs and refrains 1961, 1 score ([5] pages); 36-37 cm (Box 7, Item 077)
    For unison chorus; acc. for electric guitar, or harp/piano.
    "August 1961."
    Song four is missing.
    Contents: Minueto ven admirony (March of the grapes) -- Es tortific dogma texture (The wonderful crocodile) -- Lova, ah lova (My planet) -- A message for you.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Songs of wonder: for high voice and piano / poems by Beth Frost 1976, 1 manuscript score ([9] pages); 36 cm (Box 7, Item 078)
    Includes composer’s note.
    "For Lynne Milstein"--T.p.
    Duration 4:30.
    Contents: Untold wonders -- The horizons of time -- A magic starry night.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Songs of wonder :for high voice and piano 1976, 1 score (9 pages); 36 cm (Box 7, Item 079)
    "Aug. 29, 1976"--Colophon.
    "For Lynne Milstein."
    T.p. bears Carl Fischer label.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Songs of wonder; arr. The flute of wonder: three pieces for flute and piano 1983, 1 manuscript score (9 pages); 36 cm (Box 7, Item 080)
    Originally for voice and piano.
    "Dec. 31, 1983"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Songs of wonder; arranged The flute of wonder :three pieces for flute and piano 1983, 1 manuscript score (9 pages); 37 cm (Box 7, Item 081)
    Derived from Songs of Wonder score: flute part taped over voice part, words removed with white-out.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Songs of wonder; arranged The flute of wonder :three pieces for flute and piano 1983, 1 manuscript part; 37 cm (Box 7, Item 082)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Symphonies, no. 1 Symphony no. 1 in E♭ for orchestra 1955, 1 score (155 pages); 38 cm (Box 7, Item 083)
    "Dedicated to the memory of Serge and Natalie Koussevitzky"--Title page verso.
    "Commissioned by the Koussevitzky Music Foundation for the League of Composers' 30th anniversary"--Title page verso.
    "Awarded New York Music Critics Circle Prize as the best orchestral work by an American composer played during the season 1956-57"--Title page verso.
    "June 30, 1955"--Colophon.
    Duration 25:30.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Symphonies, no. 2 Symphony no. 2 in six movements 1965, 1 score (80 pages); 45 cm (Box 7, Item 084)
    Includes small number of Smit's markings.
    "Commissioned by Norman Rosenthal for his wife Janice"--Title page verso.
    "Jan. 12, 1965"--Colophon.
    Duration 17:00.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Symphony of dances and songs :for orchestra 1981, 1 score (146 pages); 36 cm (Box 7, Item 085)
    Includes composer's notes: 5 leaves inserted.
    "Commissioned by the United States International Communication Agency for the joint American-Yugoslav celebration of the centenary (1881-1981) of diplomatic relations."
    "9/12/81"--Colophon.
    Duration: circa 29:00.
    Contents: Psalms -- Potpourri -- Spirituals -- Kolo -- Memorial/Benediction.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 There's a certain slant of light 1990, 1 score (3 leaves); 28 cm (Box 7, Item 086)
    "1/22/90"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Thinngs all over; arr. Thinngs [sic] all over: for voice, oboe and piano 1983, 1 score (5 pages); 36 cm (Box 7, Item 087)
    "Nov. 4, 1983"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Thomas Jefferson: a narrative monodrama for baritone and piano 1988, 1 score (31 pages); 39 cm (Box 7, Item 088)
    "12.23.88, Leucadia, CA"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Toccata, piano Toccata for solo piano :1984 1984, 1 score (13 pages); 36 cm (Box 7, Item 089)
    "Commissioned by, composed for, and dedicated to Yvar Mikhashoff."
    "2.5.84"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Toccata, piano Toccata (1984): piano solo 1984, 1 score (13 pages); 35 cm (Box 7, Item 090)
    Includes markings: additions, words from Upon my garden, rides a bird, an Emily Dickinson poem written above music.
    "2.5.84, Buffalo, NY"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 A transient view :five choruses [for] unison, two, three and four equal voices unaccompanied 1967, 1 manuscript chorus score (17 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 091)
    Includes markings: additions, changes, tempo markings.
    Composer's notes (5 pages) inserted.
    "July - August/1967, Los Angeles, Calif."
    "Doubleday & Co., Inc ..."
    Duration: 7:20.
    Contents: The patron's list (variations) -- The unripe day (canon) -- Saint Valentine (antiphony) -- Monday's journey (solfeggietto) -- That far away country (requiem).
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Trumpeter swan: a cycle of five songs for soprano and piano 1987, 1 score (9 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 092)
    "March 22, 1985"--Colophon.
    Contents: Trumpeter swan -- Mirror -- Homework blues -- Dreams -- Invention.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Trumpeter swan :five songs for a little girl 1985, 1 score (13 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 093)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Trumpeter swan :five songs for a little girl: voice and piano 1987, 1 score (9 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 094)
    "This work is a vocal transformation of the composer's piano solo, Five pieces for young people"--Composer's note.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Tzadik, instrumental ensemble Tzadik: maker of miracles: for twelve players (four trios) 1983, 1 score (92 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 095)
    Originally for piano trio.
    Duration: circa 17:00.
    "Dec. 1983"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Tzadik, saxophones (4) Tzadik :for saxophone quartet 1983, 1 score (34 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 096)
    "Commissioned by and dedicated to the Amherst Saxophone Quartet."
    Includes markings: changes, additions, tempo markings.
    "July 30, 1983, Buffalo, NY"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Tzway =Two: 1935: for voice and piano 1983, 1 score (13 pages); 36 cm; Alternate title: Two (Box 8, Item 097)
    Words in Yiddish and English.
    "Tzway: soprano, piano"--Cover.
    "December 1935, New York City"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Under a tender moon :for soprano, French horn (F), viola, and harp 1990, 1 score (21 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 098)
    Poem also printed as text preceding score.
    "Commissioned by the New York State Music Teachers Association, 1990."
    "September 25, 1990, Buffalo, NY"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Variations, piano, orchestra Variations 1981, 11 parts; 32 cm (Box 8, Item 099)
    Master parts on vellum.
    For piano and orchestra.
    Piano part wanting.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Virginia sampler: a ballet for orchestra 1960, 1 score (100 pages); 36 cm (Box 8, Item 100)
    Holograph pages inserted: pages 32, 34, 35 recomposed in ink.
    Includes markings: changes, additions, and performance indications.
    "Feb. 25, 1960"--Colophon.
    Contents: Introduction -- The town -- The townspeople -- Jig (kid sister) -- Gentlemen's eccosaise -- Waltz and carousel (the lovers) -- The unidentified lady -- March for a beloved general.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Virginia sampler; arranged Virginia sampler: a ballet arranged for two pianos by the composer 1959, 1 manuscript score (40 pages); 33 cm (Box 8, Item 101)
    "1167"--Number on cover.
    "March 10, 1959, Los Angeles"--Colophon.
    "Rental Library, Carl Fischer, Inc."--Label on cover.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Yerma: a ballet from the play by Garcia Lorca 1946, 1 score (38 pages); 39 cm (Box 8, Item 102)
    For piano, bassoon, flute, trumpet (B♭).
    "June, 1946."
    "To Valerie Bettis."
    "June 12, 1946, New York City, Leo Smit"--Colophon.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Yerma: a ballet from the play by Garcia Lorca 1946, 1 score (38 pages); 39 cm + 3 parts; 32 cm (Box 8, Item 103)
    For bassoon, flute, trumpet(B♭).
    Includes indications for expanded instrumentation in score and page following score.
    Score includes markings: changes and additions.
    Trumpet part includes markings: changes.
    "First performance: June 25, 1946, New York City"--Title page verso.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Yerma 1946, 3 parts; 33 cm (Box 8, Item 104)
    Parts for bassoon, flute, and trumpet (B♭).
    Ballet, based on a play by F. García Lorca
- Arrangements and editions of works by other composers, 1940-1987, II; Item 105-123
  Arranged alphabetically by name of composer of original piece.
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990 Age of anxiety; arr. The age of anxiety: symphony no. 2 for piano and orchestra (after W. H. Auden) New York: G. Schirmer, 1950, 1 score (91 pages); 31 cm (Box 9, Item 105)
    Orchestra part arranged for second piano by Leo Smit.
    Program by composer on t.p. verso.
    Two photocopies of pages 87-94 from 1966 rev. version inserted.
    Contents: Prologue -- Seven ages -- Seven stages -- Dirge -- Masque -- Epilogue.
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990 Age of anxiety; arr. The age of anxiety: symphony no. 2 for piano and orchestra (after W.H. Auden) New York: Amberson Enterprises; G. Schirmer, 1966, 1 score (94 pages); 31 cm (Box 9, Item 106)
    Revised version; orchestra part arranged for second piano by Leo Smit
    Duration: 30:00
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990 West Side story. Selections; arranged Four movements from West Side story 1968, 1 score (20 leaves); 32 cm; Alternate title: West Side story (Box 9, Item 107)
    Excerpts from the musical.
    "Second proof Feb 20 1968"--Stamp in caption.
    "Corrections pg. 4, 5, 7, 16, 17, 20"--Inscription in margin of leaf 2.
    Negative print - white text on blue background.
    Publisher's no.: Ed. 2765.
    Contents: Jets -- Jump -- Cha-cha -- Cool.
  - Haieff, Alexei, 1914-1994 Unidentified work / Haieff; Smit. 196-?, 1 manuscript score (1 leaf); 36 cm (Box 9, Item 108)
    Possibly co-composed by Leo Smit.
    Manuscript (Photocopy)
    For solo instrument and piano.
  - Kabalevsky, Dmitry Borisovich, 1904-1987 Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 23; arranged Concerto no. 2 in G minor, op. 23, for piano and orchestra New York: Leeds Music Corp., 1946, 1 score (80 pages); 30 cm (Box 9, Item 109)
    Reduction for two pianos; edited with special annotations by Leo Smit.
  - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Czardas, piano (1884). Csárdás obstiné; arranged Csárdás obstiné (1884) :for wind quintet 1985, 1 manuscript score (19 pages); 28 cm (Box 9, Item 110)
    "Feb. 10, 1985"--Colophon.
    "For Sabrina Zolte"--Caption.
    Wanting pages 17-18.